Finding Aid for the Collection of Research Materials Related to Linguistic-Psychological Studies of Genie (pseudonym), 1895-2003, 1970-2003 LSC.0800
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 7. Photographs, ca. 1895-1993 (bulk 1970-1977)
  - Various shots of Genie, 1972 January-December (Box 59, Folder 26)
  - Various images include Genie in tub and Genie looking at Christmas tree, 1972 February (Box 59, Folder 27)
    3 x 5 color prints. From envelope labeled no. 75.
  - Genie and the Arcadia house, 1972 April, June, and December (Box 59, Folder 28)
    Color slides. Include images of her April 1972 birthday party.
  - Genie playing with finger puppets, 1972 June (Box 59, Folder 29)
    3 x 5 color prints. Small strip of negative film. From envelope labeled no. 7.
  - Play-Doh models made by Genie of her family members, 1972 June (Box 59, Folder 30)
    3 x 5 color prints. Negative film. From envelope labeled no. 56.
  - 4th of July images, 1972 July 4 (Box 59, Folder 31)
    Negative film. From envelope labeled no. 92.
  - Bathroom sink with colorful toys arrayed on top, 1972 July 8 (Box 59, Folder 32)
    Color prints. From envelope labeled no. 83.
  - Genie outside by picnic table, 1972 September (Box 59, Folder 33)
    4 x 3 b/w print.
  - Genie trimming her toe nails [with Marilyn Rigler?], 1972 October (Box 59, Folder 34)
    3 x 5 color prints. From envelope labeled no. 78.
  - Genie wearing swimming mask and fins [with Marilyn Rigler?], 1972 October (Box 59, Folder 35)
    3 x 5 color prints. From envelope labeled no. 81.
  - Genie looking at cars and into toy baby carriage, 1972 December (Box 59, Folder 36)
    Negative film.
  - Genie's dolls, 1972 December 6 (Box 59, Folder 37)
    3 x 5 color prints. From envelope labeled no. 80.
  - Genie with her mother, 1972 December 25 (Box 59, Folder 38)
    B/w contact sheets and negative film. Film envelope labeled "Negative for CS-1." Miscellaneous images are also on the film.
  - Genie at the grocery store, ca. 1973 (Box 59, Folder 39)
    3 x 5 color prints. From envelope labeled no. 86.
  - Genie outdoors at playground, ca. 1973 (Box 59, Folder 40)
    B/w prints. Negative film. Additional images on negatives. From envelope labeled no. 69
  - Genie playing with doll and exploring outside with mother?, ca. 1973 (Box 59, Folder 41)
    3 x 5 color prints. From envelope labeled no. 84.
  - Genie riding horse, ca. 1973 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Various shots at outdoor park, including Genie riding a horse, ca. 1973 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    3 x 5 color prints. From envelope labeled no. 106.
  - Various of Genie with others and one school portrait, 1973 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    Color prints. From envelope labeled no. 5.
  - Genie at her birthday party with Pam [?], 1973 April 8 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    3 x 5 b/w prints.
  - Mainly headshots of Genie, 1973 January (Box 60, Folder 5)
    3 x 5 color prints. Negative film (includes images not found in prints). From envelope labeled no. 70.
  - Genie in various environments, 1973 February (Box 60, Folder 6)
    3 x 5 color prints. Negative film. From envelope labeled no. 52. Genie playing in snow at Geller cabin; at school; and with her mother.
  - Various images of Genie, 1973 February-April (Box 60, Folder 7)
    Color slides. Includes some images of Genie with her mother.
  - Genie at the beach, 1973 March (Box 60, Folder 8)
    B/w contact sheets and negative film.
  - Genie at the beach with others, flying kite, 1973 March (Box 60, Folder 9)
    3.5 x 4.5 prints. From envelope labeled no. 103.
  - Genie with her mother and at airport and on plane for Palo Alto trip, 1973 May (Box 60, Folder 10)
    3.5 x 4.5 prints.. From envelope labeled no. 73.
  - Genie at airport and on plane for Palo Alto trip, 1973 May (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Various images of Genie, 1973 May-August; 1973 November (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Genie alone, in school environment, and at beach., 1973 June; 1974 March (Box 60, Folder 13)
  - Genie at Yosemite kayaking, 1973 September 27 (Box 60, Folder 14)
    3.25 x 4.5 b/w prints. Contact strips and negative film. From envelope labeled no. 82.
  - Various images of Genie, 1973 November-December (Box 60, Folder 15)
  - Various images of children and young adults washing a car, 1973 November 12 (Box 60, Folder 16)
    Negative film. Film envelope was addressed to: Wiley, I. 6722 N. Golden West.
  - Genie eating at McDonald's, 1973 December (Box 60, Folder 17)
    3.5 x 3.5 color prints. Negative film. From envelope labeled no. 1
  - Various of Genie eating McDonald's, at the park, riding a horse, 1973 December (Box 60, Folder 18)
    3.5 x 3.5 color prints. Negative film. From envelope labeled no. 77
  - Genie at Griffith Park, ca. 1974 (Box 60, Folder 19)
    Negative film. From envelope labeled no. 10.
  - Genie experiencing a tantrum, ca. 1974 (Box 60, Folder 20)
    Negative film. From envelope marked no. 51.
  - Genie's drawings, ca. 1974 (Box 60, Folder 21)
    3.5 x 5 color prints.
  - T-scope images, ca. 1974 (Box 60, Folder 22)
    Negative film. Various simple images, possibly for visual stimuli of test subject.
  - Genie playing with blocks and in tub, ca. 1974 March (Box 60, Folder 23)
  - Genie at Rigler kitchen table, 1974 March (Box 60, Folder 24)
    3.5 x 5 color prints. From envelope marked no. 95.
  - Genie in tub and playing a tambourine [with David Rigler?], 1974 March (Box 60, Folder 25)
    3.5 x 5 color prints. Also includes the negative film. From envelope marked no. 48.
  - Genie with Larry Solow learning sign language, 1974 March (Box 60, Folder 26)
    Negative film. From envelope marked no. 50.
  - Genie at Griffith Park, 1974 March 2 (Box 60, Folder 27)
    3.5 x 5 color prints. From envelope marked no. 94.
  - Genie in classroom with unidentified adults [learning sign language?], 1974 March 26-27 (Box 60, Folder 28)
    3.5 x 5 color prints. From envelope marked no. 96.
  - Individual shots of Genie, 1974 March 27 (Box 60, Folder 29)
    3.5 x 5 color prints. From envelope marked no. 72. Includes small piece of negative film.
  - Various images of Genie, 1974 February-April (Box 60, Folder 30)
  - Genie with adults in classroom using balancing objects and outdoors exploring, 1974 April (Box 60, Folder 31)
    2.5 x 3.5 color prints. From envelope marked no. 98.
  - Wrapping paper and colored containers, 1974 April (Box 60, Folder 32)
    3.5 x 5 color prints. From envelope marked no. 98.
  - Various images of Genie, 1974 April; 1974 June-July (Box 60, Folder 33)
  - Genie at Salvin School, 1974 May (Box 60, Folder 34)
    Color prints. Cropped images mounted on yellow index cards. From envelope marked no. 102.
  - Genie's bed and various objects, 1974 May 7 (Box 60, Folder 35)
    Color prints. From envelope marked no. 73.
  - Genie at camp with Jean [Butler?], 1974 June (Box 60, Folder 36)
  - Various images of Genie, 1974 July, September, November; 1975 March (Box 60, Folder 37)
  - Genie getting testing at San Diego Speech and Hearing, 1974 October (Box 60, Folder 38)
    Color prints and negative film.
  - Genie pulling on mouth, 1974 October (Box 60, Folder 39)
    3.5 x 5 color print. From enveloped labeled no. 4.
  - Genie at beach, playing in water and in kayak, ca. 1975 (Box 60, Folder 40)
    3.5 x 5 b/w prints. From envelope labeled no. 2.
  - Genie exercising [with Marilyn Rigler?] and at a petting zoo, ca. 1975 (Box 60, Folder 41)
    3.5 x 5 color prints. From envelope marked no. 58.
  - Genie staring at water, ca. 1975 (Box 60, Folder 42)
    3.5 x 5 color print.
  - Genie with mother, ca. 1975 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    B/w 8 x 11 print.
  - Letter from Danielle [?] regarding photographs of Susan, ca. 1975 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    Two letters to the Riglers with some information on contact sheets and photo shots.
  - Miscellaneous shots several of which include Genie, ca. 1975 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    B/w contact sheet and negative film.
  - School portrait of Genie, ca. 1975 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    Color prints, various sizes.
  - Genie and various items/toys, 1975 February; 1975 April (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Various shots of Genie, 1975 February-1975 May; 1975 November (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Various images include Genie on carousel, wearing electrodes during testing, wearing her glasses, petting a horse, 1975 August (Box 61, Folder 7)
    3.5 x 5 color prints. From envelope labeled no. 57
  - Genie at the Mansfield home playing with exercise equipment and with other girls, 1975 December (Box 61, Folder 8)
    3.5 x 5 color prints. Also includes the negative film. From envelope marked no. 67.
  - Two unidentified women sitting in wheelchairs, 1975 December (Box 61, Folder 9)
    Color print and color slide.
  - Genie's exam at Childrens Hospital of Los Angeles, 1976 February 19 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Clinical testing instruments, 1976 March (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Signs and gestures, 1976 March (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Street Gestalt images, 1976 March (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - Genie's graduation ceremony, 1976 June (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - Genie with Riglers, 1977 January (Box 61, Folder 15)
  - Genie with dog and with baby, 1977 May (Box 61, Folder 16)
  - Detailed list and identification of shots, 1992 December 23 (Box 61, Folder 17)
  - Genie with Marilyn Rigler, ca. 1993 (Box 61, Folder 18)
    4 x 6 color prints.
- 8. Research, ca. 1938-1994 (bulk 1970-1977)
  Series consists of administrative paperwork related to personnel issues for research team members, correspondence and memorandums, interview notes and transcriptions, and examples of Genie's artwork. Series also contains items related to specific research issues, including material from consultants, essays and articles, related case study examples, pedagogical material, and assorted printed material. Some of these materials, due to privacy concerns, may be inaccessible to researchers. Please consult the Manuscripts Librarian in advance so that access arrangements can be made as appropriate.
  Arranged in subseries A-H as follows:
  8A. Administrative
  8B. Correspondence
  8C. Family history
  8D. Genie's artwork
  8E. Language, sleep and social behavior
  8F. Miscellaneous
  8G. Notes
  8H. Testing.
  - 8A. Administrative papers, 1970-1981 (bulk 1970-1977)
    Subseries consists of employee status forms and job descriptions for research team members, invoices, correspondence, and miscellaneous material.
    - Personnel issues for studies, 1970 December 23-1972 August 8 (Box 61, Folder 19)
      Memos, employee status forms, and job descriptions.
    - Various material on study consultant David Freedman, ca. 1971 February (Box 61, Folder 20)
      Includes CV, papers, and journal reprints.
    - Correspondence--Dunlop, H.B., 1971 June 17 (Box 61, Folder 21)
      To George Donnell regarding fund disbursement.
    - Memo from Howard Hansen regarding new position for NIMH research contract, 1971 September 1 (Box 61, Folder 22)
    - Invoice--Braff, Reba, 1971 September 28 (Box 61, Folder 23)
    - Invoices--Rigler, Marilyn, 1971 September 30-1975 March 21 (Box 61, Folder 24)
      Invoice for research consultant services.
    - Job descriptions for research assistants, ca. 1972 (Box 61, Folder 25)
    - Note from Marina [?] regarding payment for work, ca. 1972 (Box 61, Folder 26)
    - IRS material, 1972 March-1973 December (Box 61, Folder 27)
      Includes employee statements, correspondence, and notes for Marilyn Rigler, Melanie Levin, and Caroline Carr.
    - Employee status forms for Barbara Goldenberg, 1972 June 13 (Box 61, Folder 28)
    - Employee status forms for Susan Curtiss, 1972 June 13-1973 July 3 (Box 61, Folder 29)
    - Employee status forms for Stephen Krashen, 1972 July 19; 1972 August 1 (Box 61, Folder 30)
    - Employee status forms from Childrens Hospital of Los Angeles, 1972 September-October (Box 61, Folder 31)
    - Partial list of personnel associated with research on Genie, ca. 1973 (Box 61, Folder 32)
      Includes informal organization chart.
    - Employee status forms and report of performance evaluation for Karyn Avery, 1973 October 17-1974 October 22 (Box 61, Folder 33)
    - Invoice from Marina McIntire for consulting services, 1974 October 10 (Box 61, Folder 34)
    - People who worked with Genie on staff or as volunteers, ca. 1975 (Box 61, Folder 35)
    - Personnel associated with research on Genie, ca. 1975 (Box 61, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence--Various requests for information, 1975-1981 (Box 61, Folder 37)
      Various letters to David Rigler.
  - 8B. Correspondence, 1970-1976
    Subseries consists entirely of correspondence to and from various team members, consultants, and other pertinent external parties.
    - Kent, James T. to Jean E. Matusinka, Deputy District Attorney, regarding synopsis of Genie's condition, 1970 December 1 (Box 61, Folder 38)
    - Wursten, Helmut to Howard Hansen regarding testing, 1970 December 2 (Box 61, Folder 39)
    - Communications with various case consultants, 1971-1974 (Box 61, Folder 40)
    - Shurley, Jay to Howard Hansen regarding Genie's sleep testing, 1971 March 30 (Box 61, Folder 41)
    - Kent, James T. to Susan Omansky, 1971 May 17 (Box 61, Folder 42)
    - Freedman, David A. to David Rigler, 1971 May 21 (Box 61, Folder 43)
    - Various incoming and outgoing correspondence, 1971 July 22-1975 April 4 (Box 61, Folder 44)
    - Rigler, David to Sue Omansky, 1971 August 7 (Box 61, Folder 45)
    - [Bennett], Tina to David Rigler regarding tape transcripts, ca. 1972 November 25 (Box 61, Folder 46)
    - Braff, Reba--Speech therapy material, 1972 January 13; 1972 July 12 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Hewes, Gordon to David Rigler, 1972 October 5, 1974 October 27 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Brown, Warren to David Rigler, ca. 1973 (Box 62, Folder 3)
      Description of electrophysiological study of Genie.
    - Block, Jeanne, 1973 December 6 (Box 62, Folder 4)
      Summary letter to David Rigler regarding observations.
    - Requests for information Genie's case from professional colleagues, 1973 September 10; 1976 April, May (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Rigler, David to Fred Adams, Department of Public Social Services, 1974 January 8 (Box 62, Folder 6)
      Regarding Irene Wiley's capacity for work.
    - Rigler, David to Dr. Read Tuddenham, 1974 January 8 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Laine, Janice E. to the Riglers, 1974 May 2 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Metcalf, David R. to David Rigler regarding EEG studies, 1974 May 9 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Shattuck, Roger to David Rigler, 1974 May 9 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Metcalf, David R. to David Rigler and Howard Hansen, 1974 May 10 (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Samar, Vincent J.--Incoming and outgoing, 1974 June 5-July 7 (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - Dinwoodie, Marian to David Rigler, 1974 June 11 (Box 62, Folder 13)
    - Fromkin, Victoria to David Rigler, 1974 June 17 (Box 62, Folder 14)
    - Fromkin, Victoria to Vincent Samar, 1974 June 19 (Box 62, Folder 15)
    - Torgoff, Irv to David Rigler, 1974 June 26 (Box 62, Folder 16)
    - Neustein, Harry B. to David Rigler regarding approval for clinical investigation, 1974 July 3 (Box 62, Folder 17)
    - Rigler, David to David A. Munro, 1974 October 21-25 (Box 62, Folder 18)
      Includes Munro's original letter.
    - Borstein, Harry to Marilyn Rigler, 1974 November 4 (Box 62, Folder 19)
    - Apthorp, James S., 1974 November 5 (Box 62, Folder 20)
      Letter regarding request for occupational therapy for Genie.
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1974 August-1975 October (Box 62, Folder 21)
    - Herron, E. Wayne to David Rigler. Critique of MH21191-04, 1974 December 12 (Box 62, Folder 22)
    - Hiatt, Frederick S. to Dr. Stuart Siegel, 1975 February 6 (Box 62, Folder 23)
    - Rigler, David to Jay Shurley, 1975 March 21 (Box 62, Folder 24)
    - Schrier, Shirley to David Rigler, 1975 March 24 (Box 62, Folder 25)
    - Natani, Kirmach to David Rigler, 1975 April 2 (Box 62, Folder 26)
      Includes attached reprint of paper.
    - Rigler, David to Gloria Shepard, 1975 June 4 (Box 62, Folder 27)
    - Natani, Kirmach to David Rigler, 1975 June 11 (Box 62, Folder 28)
    - Rigler, David to Stephen Krashen, 1975 October 20 (Box 62, Folder 29)
    - Reynolds, Cecil R. to David Rigler, 1976 September 9 (Box 62, Folder 30)
    - Request for copies of journal articles on Genie, 1976 October-1977 July (Box 62, Folder 31)
  - 8C. Family history, 1970-1972
    Subseries consists of information and material gathered during research that provides insight into Genie's family history and her home situation before discovery.
    - Copy of original charges made against the Wileys, 1970 November 10 (Box 62, Folder 32)
    - Transcript of Irene Wiley interviewed by Dr. Hansen, 1970 November 23 (Box 62, Folder 33)
    - Original notes and interview material of Irene Wiley, 1970 November 23-1974 December 30 (Box 62, Folder 34)
      Includes photocopies of family genealogical register.
    - Transcriptions of interview with DPSS worker, Stephanie Heinzmann, 1970 December 8 (Box 62, Folder 35)
      Original audio reel to be found in Series 1.
    - Hansen, Howard--Notes from interview with Irene Wiley, 1971 April 2 (Box 62, Folder 36)
    - Knapp, Vrinda--Notes from interviews with Irene Wiley, 1971 Fall (Box 62, Folder 37)
    - Preliminary psychological autopsy of Clark Wiley, 1971 November (Box 62, Folder 38)
      Includes photocopy of note to Wiley's attorney, Lowell A. Hahn, stipulating his burial requests.
    - Transcription of David Rigler's handwritten notes regarding meeting with Feezell, Hansen, and Knapp, 1971 December 13 (Box 62, Folder 39)
    - Floor diagrams--hand drafted layout and dimensions of 6722 Golden West, 1972 February 9 (Box 62, Folder 40)
  - 8D. Genie's artwork, 1970-1977
    Subseries consists of a variety of artwork done by Genie while in the hospital and throughout her work with the research team and the Riglers. Present are drawings in pencil, crayon, marker, and paint on various types of paper. Also included are several craft projects.
    - Styrofoam ball carved with face, ca. 1972 (Box 44)
    - List of drawings made by Genie, 1970-1975 (Box 62, Folder 41)
    - Drawing on blue construction paper, ca. 1971 (Box 62, Folder 42)
    - Various drawings including one of a bird, 1971 October 2-1971 October 22 (Box 62, Folder 43)
    - Photocopies of various drawings, with notations by Marilyn Rigler, 1971 October 16 (Box 62, Folder 44)
    - Small pencil drawing by Genie, 1971 December 22 (Box 62, Folder 45)
    - Handmade coloring book., ca. 1972 (Box 62, Folder 46)
    - Drawing exercises, 1972 February 9 (Box 62, Folder 47)
    - Various drawings including some with Genie's writing, 1972 June 16; 1972 August 19 (Box 62, Folder 48)
    - Various drawings by Genie including after visits to circus and zoo, 1972 July 29-1972 October 20 (Box 62, Folder 49)
    - Various drawings by Genie, 1973 (Box 62, Folder 50)
    - Pictures of Marilyn, 1973 May 29 (Box 62, Folder 51)
    - Self-portraits drawn by Genie, 1973 May 30 (Box 62, Folder 52)
    - Attempts to color between lines with crayon, 1973 December 17 (Box 62, Folder 53)
    - Drawings by Genie on yellow tablet, ca. 1974 (Box 62, Folder 54)
    - Various drawings including of bears, 1974 (Box 62, Folder 55)
    - Various drawings by Genie including birthday greeting to Marilyn, 1974 October 8-1974 December (Box 62, Folder 56)
    - Pencil drawing of a baby, ca. 1975 (Box 62, Folder 57)
    - Drawings done with blue marker, 1976 February 19 (Box 62, Folder 58)
    - Drawing of Mrs. Mansfield, 1977 April 29 (Box 62, Folder 59)
    - Collages using magazine images, 1972 January-December (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Craft book entitled "I want an egg for breakfast.", ca. 1973 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Susan's Camp Book. Includes color photographs of Susan in various activities, ca. 1974 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Various drawings including some of Genie's grandparents and mother, 1974 March 5: 1974 November 12, 30 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Various drawings, 1974-1975; undated (Box 79, Folder 8)
      Includes photocopies of some drawings, in addition to original artwork.
    - Various drawings with paint, 1970 November 20; 1970 November 30 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Various drawings with crayon, 1970 November 20-November 30 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Various drawings, 1971 January 24-1971 April 12 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Various drawings including one of Tori (Rigler's dog), 1971 August 27 and August 29 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Various drawings on brown paper with crayon, 1971 October 5-30 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Various drawings in crayon and pen, 1972 January 23-1972 December 2 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Done on cardboard, 1972 August 10-1972 October 2 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Various drawings, 1973 January 6-1973 March 17 (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Various drawings including one of "monster", 1970 January 23-1970 November 2 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Various drawings including object and geometric shapes, 1971 January 20-1975 January 7 (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Examples of Genie's printing, 1971 January 29-1971 December 10 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Various drawings, 1971 March 23-December 2 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Examples of Genie's printing, 1972 January 30-1972 December 15 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Various drawings including some of teachers, 1973 January-June (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Printing exercises, 1973 January 29-1973 December (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Various including some of children, 1974 January 9; 1974 November 5 (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - Drawings using paint, 1970 November 23-ca. 1970 December 3 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Drawings using paint, 1971 January, April (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Drawings using paint, 1972 March 1; 1972 November-December (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Examples of printing, 1972 December 11; 1973 June 15 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Human figures drawn with marker, 1974 February (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Drawings done with paint at Barnsdall Park, 1972 March 8 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Various drawings on oversized white paper, 1972 October 24; 1972 November 14 (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Various drawings, 1973 January; 1973 March 29 (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Various drawings on oversized paper, ca. 1974 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Various drawings on oversized paper, 1974 March-May (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - 8E. Language, sleep, and social behaviors, 1962-1976 (bulk 1970-1976)
    Subseries consists of various material related to Genie's language acquisition, sleeping patterns, and behavior including questionnaires, diagnostic material, meeting transcriptions, material on related studies and research, psychological assessments, and other miscellaneous material.
    - Activity questionnaires, 1973 December 24-1974 August 1 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Automatic and propositional speech material., 1973 January (Box 63, Folder 2)
      Diana Van Lancker summary handout.
    - Battison, Robin / Genie's gestural behavior, 1974 April 11 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Bellugi, Ursula and Edward Klima--Correspondence and consultation report on Genie, 1971 March 3; 1972 September 25 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Bellugi, Ursula and Edward Klima--Material regarding language and speech development, 1968 March-1972 March; undated (Box 63, Folder 5)
      Reports, correspondence, notes, journal articles.
    - Bennett, Tina Lynne / Development of attention-getting strategies in Genie, ca. 1975 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Block, Jack and Jeanne Block--Transcription of meeting with David Rigler, 1971 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Block, Jack and Jeanne Block--Consultation material, 1971 February 5 (Box 63, Folder 8)
      Includes transcription of taped meeting and consultation report.
    - Block, Jeanne--Consultative site visit report, 1973 December 6 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Bloom, Lois / Cognitive and linguistic aspects of early language development, 1972 November 21 (Box 63, Folder 10)